朽木
十年荏苒 再次踏上那一成不变的山丘
Ten years gone, 'proaching that self-same hill.
我原以为会命丧此地
I thought to lay me down and rise no more.
离我远点儿 妖风要来了
Give me wide berth! That's just passed wind!
也可能只是个臭屁
Possibly worse.
在永远阖上双眼之前
Before eyes close for good and all...
我只想再见我的琼妮·斯塔布斯一次
I'd once again see my Joanie Stubbs...
告诉她
show her a sign of...
卡拉米蒂·简对失去挚爱的遗憾
loving regret from Calamity Jane to her darling.
以及对怀尔德·比尔去世的悲哀
And, too, at the grave of Wild Bill.
哼 我还得处理一个左脸生疮的王八蛋
Oof, I've a left-cheek ass blister's a percolating son of a bitch.
行 就放那
Good, right there.
南达科他州
建州典庆
宝石酒馆
早上好 老大
Morning, Boss!
把那瘸子叫来
Get me the gimp.
-朱厄尔 -干嘛
- Jewel! - What?
给老子上来
Get up here.
我炉子上煮着东西呢 艾尔
Have something on the stove, Al!
那你就就快点煮好啊
Well, once you finish burning it, then.
-早啊 医生 -早上好 艾尔
- Morning, Doc. - Morning, Al.
你现在有空吗
Uh, at liberty... are you just now?
怎么 你想跳舞吗
Why, you wanna dance?
那些是要干嘛用的
What'd that be about?
用来做电话线杆
Fashioning into telephone poles.
还嫌我们这儿的电话线杆不够多吗
Ain't we got enough of them damn things already?
计划是要给每家铺面都接上电话线
Plan's to put lines in every business.
要与时俱进哟
Catch up with the times!
不太舒服是吗 长官
Out of sorts, would you say, Commander?
一点小毛病 不足挂齿
Half a stride short of fully fit.
体重莫名减了几斤是吧
Light, somewhat, a few pounds.
脸色也有点苍白
And some bit pallid, too.
老天 医生 你还不如一枪崩了我
Ah, Jesus, just shoot me, Doc.
告诉我今天星期几 艾尔
Name the day of the week, Al.
星期几之间有什么区别吗
The fuck difference does the day make?
劳烦您务必告诉我
I'd have you but say the name.
那就是星期二吧 你个吓人的臭老头
Tuesday then, you half a scarecrow-looking cocksucker.
今天是星期五
Friday, it is.
把星期五记成星期二
Mistaking Friday for Tuesday.
先给我挖个坑吧
Well, secure my burial plot.
你的体温比正常要高两度
Well, your temperature's two degrees above normal,
印堂发黑
features drawn,
面色发黄
flesh of a yellowish cast,
眼看就他妈的要病入膏肓了
Pending fucking developments...
你最好别沾酒了
I'd have you forbear from spirits.
-悉听尊便 -你别
- Under advisement. - Oh, no, no, no.
别跟我开玩笑 也别用这种轻蔑的语气
Don't you humor me, nor talk down to me neither,
也不要不请自来地到处鬼混
nor fix to mix in where you ain't been invited.
你怎么能这样说我
Whilst you comport the very like to me?
你的肝脏出了问题 艾尔
You went somewhat wrong at your liver, Al,
还是你自己一手造成的
is what you've God damn done!
酒保 你是睁眼瞎还是怎么的
Bar you being out-and-out blind,
你明知道他病了
you already know he's ill.
一分钟前
Minute past,
我还跟丹说呢 老大气色不好
words to Dan, "Boss is looking poorly.
看上去像是病了
Out of sorts."
他看上去像是没病吗 你这只蠢驴
Don't he look outta sorts, you goddamn donkey?
在他的诊断化验结果出来前
He is to forbear from spirits of any kind,
他什么酒都不能沾
until he's assayed and diagnosed.
要知道他完全可以去街上随便买酒喝
You know he'll just endeavor to import spirits in off the street?
那你就不准他喝啊
Well, you're not to allow it!
说来容易做来难啊
That's easier told than saddled and rode.
那你们就把他直接吊死啊 妈的
Well then, go ahead and hang him, goddamn it!
或者一枪崩了他
Blow his fuckin' head off!
这样大家都省事了
Save us all some time!
起床气有点重啊
Wrong side of the damn bed!
埃尔斯沃斯夫人 在下查理·乌特
Mrs. Ellsworth! Charlie Utter.
天呀
Oh my.
能久别重逢真是太开心了
What a grand surprise after such a piece of time.
我也是 乌特先生
For me, Mr. Utter, as well.
索菲亚 快下来吧
Sofia! Come on!
恕我冒昧 埃尔斯沃斯夫人
Am I past my place, Ms. Ellsworth,
你是为了银行的事回来的吗
asking if it's banking brings you back these parts?
对 是银行的事
Banking, yes.
我所投资的朽木镇银行
My interest in the Deadwood Bank,
现在规模越来越大了
which is an expanding institution...
埃尔斯沃斯夫人 这要放到几年前
Few years back, Mrs. Ellsworth,
会有人教那种无礼的家伙好好做人
bad manners like that woulda lead to a lesson in courtesy!
所幸还有像您这样难得的人在
Continuing grateful for hard-won maturity.
索菲亚 来和这位先生叙叙旧
Sofia, a gentleman wishes to renew acquaintances
查理·乌特向索菲亚小姐问好
Charlie Utter saying hello to Miss Sofia.
十年仿佛就在
The 10 years went past like--
弹指一挥间
somebody snapped their fingers.
您也好 乌特先生
Hello back, Mr. Utter.
-很高兴再见你 -谢谢
- It's lovely to see you again. - Thank you.
如果可以的话 我很乐意用马车
Hey, I'd be happy to convey you all
载二位去朽木镇上
into Deadwood camp in my wagon.
能有您相伴 还能搭个顺风车当然很好
As we would be for the transport, and your good company.
那就快上车吧
Oh well, come on.
希望我们还能赶上建州庆典
I hope we're in time for the statehood celebration.
我尽可能快马加鞭吧
Go as quick as I'm able.
嘿 甜心
Hey, sweetheart.
我帮你拿行李吧
Help you with that luggage.
谢了 我自己可以
Very kind, I'm okay.
我猜你会在镇上住一阵子吧
Well, I assume you'll be staying in town, darling.
失陪了
Pardon me.
去你那一晚要多少钱呢
There a price we can offer for that information?
你误会了
You have me wrong.
哦 你在这呢
Oh, there you are!
你好呀
Hello there.
请载我一程 我会付钱的
Looking for a ride. I can pay.
南达科他州加入了美国联邦
South Dakota marrying the United States.
哦 看她们学得多认真啊 赛斯
Oh! See, they're paying attention, Seth.
-早上好 小姑娘 -爸爸早啊
- Morning, miss. - Morning, Papa.
看来布洛克家族已准备好参加建州庆典了
Bullock clan ready for the statehood festivities.
你准备好了吗 老公
Are you ready, husband,
今天可有很多大人物到场
considering the visiting delegates include
还包括加州议员
the senator from California?
若是去庆祝的话 是的 我准备好了
To celebrate, yes, I am.
我倒挺想信你的
I'm tempted to believe you.
庆典煎饼出炉啦
Statehood pancakes coming out!
让开
Clear the way!
好啦 好啦 小家伙
All right, all right, little man.
这小子一心一意的 跟他老爸一样
Single-minded, this boy, like his old man.
你觉得这是优点吧
A virtue in your estimation.
愿主保佑我们享用圣餐
Lord, bless these gifts we ready to receive,
赐我们恩典来助我们冷静面对
and grant us grace to meet level-headed
今天可能遇到的
what challenges may come this day...
任何难关 挑衅或是恶人
no matter the provocation by lesser or evil men.
阿门
Amen.
今天
On this day
在我们的建州庆典上
of our statehood celebration...
我们要赞扬一位无比慷慨的人
...we honor a man who with unexampled generosity
他为朽木镇作出了巨大贡献
has give of himself to our Deadwood community.
尽管他已不再居住此地
Though no longer residing amongst us,
以加州为家
he calls California now his home.
他在南达科他州的朽木镇的
The man bases his considerable mining and real estate interest
矿业和房地产业上的投资十分可观
here in Deadwood, South Dakota.
现在有请各位
I ask you please
与我一起欢迎 来自伟大的加州
to greet with me now, the honorable
尊敬的的新科参议员
junior senator from the great state of California,
乔治·安布罗斯·赫斯特
George Ambrose Hearst!
大家早上好
Good morning to all!
首先我要感谢法纳姆镇长
And great thanks to Mayor Farnum
满溢着热情的欢迎致辞
for his generous words of welcome.
这使我十分动容
It moves me greatly,
能在多年后回到此地见证
returning after years have passed to witness
经由时间
the changes wrought
巧思和创新
by time,
所发生的日新月异的变化
ingenuity, and invention.
但无可否认的是
Though none would deny the facts
历史上所付出的代价
the cost of past,
由在场的各位所知晓的
we who gather have known together...
其中的一部分历史
Some portion of which must still
是用血的代价换来的
be measured in blood.
但朽木镇
Yet, the Deadwood community
已经日渐成熟
does enter its adulthood...
还真是振奋人心啊
And don't our spirits raise,
你个背后插刀 杀人放火
you murdering, conniving,
烧杀抢掠的狗东西
thieving cocksucker.
智谋与勇敢
Resourceful and resolute,
是新建的南达科他州的一重要部分
a vital part of the new-made state of South Dakota,
而本州
and this state
也是我们伟大祖国的一重要部分
a vital part of our fine country.
上天保佑
Amen to that!
谢谢您 议员
Thank you, Senator!
差两间房旅馆就客满了 崔西
Hotel's but two rooms short of fully occupied, Trixie,
游行还在如火如荼地进行
with the parade yet still in full swing.
恭喜你了 史达先生
Congratulations then, Mr. Star,
以及布洛克警长
to you and Marshal Bullock.
快用砖头给我脑袋来一下
Maybe mark the moment
好纪念这一刻
braining me with a fucking brick!
我得尽快娶你进门
I'd sooner put a ring on your finger.
那得先看这个孩子能不能活下来
Once first we've seen does the baby survive.
这就是你脑海里想结婚的唯一
That being, in your scripture, matrimony's single
理由和目的吗
reason and purpose.
我这个年纪的妓女能怀上孩子
Ain't we already awash in the miracle
不就已经是天大的奇迹了吗
of a whore of my vintage being pregnant at all?
那要不要穿的喜庆一点
Well, why not wear a sign, then?
像是从头到脚穿个大红袍
Dress in red, head to toe?
拜托了 崔西 你不该去外头露面
Please, Trixie. You oughtn't show your face outside.
我会吩咐人送来你喜欢的冰柠檬水
Lemonade's on its way with chips of ice, how you like.
休息一下
Rest now.
我感觉要挂了
I just got the fuck up.
好好休息吧
Rest.
亲妈爆炸的混账东西
Murdering motherless cocksucker.
赫斯特议员 尊敬的阁下
Oh, Senator Hearst! Your honor!
参议员 在他们被屠杀的十周年
On this 10th anniversary of them being butchered,
纪念日之际 我向你转达来自
I convey to you, Senator, memorial greetings
矿工埃尔斯沃斯和妓女珍的悼念问候
from the miner Ellsworth and prostitute Jen.
-但只有这两个人知道 -等等
- But two of the who knows how many - Hold it!
你为了赚钱做了多么肮脏的工作
you've done for while making your moneyed progress!
你难道不知道
Have I missed word of your appointment
新参议员的任命的消息吗
to some position of authority?
你问我知不知道你
Have I missed word of yours,
你个秃顶贱人
you bald-pated cunt?!
参议员 你最好小心点
Better watch yourself, Senator!
赫斯特先生
Mr. Hearst?
不是吗 先生
For ain't it so, sir.
当你在暗爽时
It's the thieving and throat-cutting,
他们被掠夺 被割喉
them's bloodied and dead in the mud,
浑身是血 烂在泥里
as still stiffens the member in your long-johns!
看在上帝的份儿上 他们为什么不走呢
Well, why not press forward, for Christ's sake?
等着她爆炸吗
Set herself aflame?
不 我不应该
Nor, ought I fail to remark
站在这个有利位置说道
the semblance from this vantage twixt
你的巧取豪夺的日子已经到头了
your very mug and a snatch has gone haired-over-sideways.
法纳姆镇长 这是
Mayor Farnum! It's a...
看来崔西并没有丢失她的天赋
Trixie hasn't lost her gift.
事实上她确实是
She ain't for a fact.
岁月都改变不了这一点
Time can't touch that.
让这个老狐狸
...letting this slimy cocksucker slither his way
在我们镇子里横行霸道
into our camp's inner workings!
你就是一个肮脏下流妓女
And aren't you the vile bodying
的卑鄙化身 快走
of a gutter-mouth trollop and tramp! Go.
-正如你是一个无耻的杀人犯 -走
- As you are of a murdering shitheel! - Now.
崔西
Trixie!
你没别的事儿干吗 崔西
What's left still to do, Trixie?
你想从楼梯上摔下去
Pitch yourself down the stairs?
然后断送我们孩子的幸福吗
End any chance of our child's well-being?
妈的
Jesus wept!
怎么了
What is it?
被你他妈的说中了 有点不对劲
Something amiss, as you fuckin' foresaw.
准备要生了吗
Ready for the doc we are?
-你快去找医生吧 -好
- Off you go then to fetch him. - Okay.
会没事的
I'll be good.
警长
Marshal!
乌特先生
Mr. Utter!
-你好 -你好 姑娘们
- Hello. - Hello, girls.
-查理叔叔向你们问好 -查理叔叔
- Greetings from Uncle Charlie. - Uncle Charlie!
很高兴再次见到你们俩
It's lovely to see you both again.
布洛克太太
Mrs. Bullock.
我记得你的阅读课上得很好
I remember your reading lessons so well.
埃尔斯沃斯太太和她的女儿
Mrs. Ellsworth here and her daughter,
需要一个房间
they need a room.
我告诉他们镇上最好的酒店就在那里
I told them best hotel in town's right there.
也许对酒店老板来说
Perhaps installing Mrs. Ellsworth in a suite
给埃尔斯沃斯太太安置一间套房
would be the considerate thing
是件挺体面的事儿
for the hotel's owner to do?
是的 当然
Yes, it would.
埃尔斯沃斯太太 你有订到房间吗
Mrs. Ellsworth, was there a room available?
呃 似乎
Uh, it-it seems...
我们得到了最后一个
we've secured the very last one.
看来今天是我的幸运日
Must be my lucky day.
我送你上楼
I'll walk you upstairs.
你一直以来都活在我的回忆中
You, having so lived in recollection,
警长
Marshal,
能再次见到你真是太高兴了
it is my considerable happiness to see you again.
埃尔斯沃斯太太 我比你见到我更高兴
No less a happiness, Mrs. Ellsworth, than of seeing you for me.
如同往日美梦再次苏醒
As a dream might come alive to draw a breath.
说得太多了
Said overmuch.
我发誓不会再来 但我知道我绝对会的
Vowed I wouldn't, but I absolutely knew I would.
你来之前为什么不写信告诉我
Why didn't you write of your arrival?
我没把握
Not sure.
我懂了
I see.
我想知道
I wonder,
布洛克先生
Mr. Bullock, if all
我的不速而来是否
unwitting...
给你带来了什么麻烦
I may have done something to upset an apple cart.
一点也不
Not at all.
很高兴再次见到你们俩
It's a pleasure to see you both again.
怎么了
What?
没什么 妈妈
Nothing, Mama.
布洛克 嘿 警长
Bullock! Hey, Marshal!
应该找个人来通知我
Just the man I was looking for, could warned me
埃尔斯沃斯太太的到来 查理
of Mrs. Ellsworth's return, Charlie.
妈的 别说你了 我都感到惊讶
How the fuck, when I was surprised myself?
至少不要把她安在我这该死的酒店里
Very least not deposit her in my goddamn hotel!
嘿 别说那些儿女情长的小事了
Hey, if you're finished rapping my knuckles,
我们谈些大老爷们的事
I got some more manly matters to discuss.
我洗耳恭听 查理
I'm all ears, Charlie.
赫斯特想买我的地
Hearst wants to buy my land.
先是让中介拿着钱袋在我面前晃荡
Dangling big paydays through third parties.
然后他今天会自己过来
He's coming today hisself.
-你准备接受吗 -我都这把年纪了
- Are you disposed? - My age, I'd...
要不接受的话那也太傻吧
be a fool not to chew on it some.
很明显 布洛克把眼睛挪开了
Which, uh, evidently, Bullock that looks away,
皱着眉头
scowling like he is,
好像并不赞成此事
don't approve of.
乌特的朋友布洛克这样想的
Utter's pal Bullock
如果乌特卖掉了他的土地
figures if Utter sold off his land,
那乌特除了坐在那间老酒馆里发呆
nothing for Utter to do but sit wondering,
别无他事可做 那他到底为什么
in that old saloon, why in hell
要卖掉他花了一辈子
he'd sold the thing he'd spent his life
才买来的 并为他所用的东西呢
getting situated to buy and keep to work it himself?
赫斯特不配拥有你的土地 查理
Hearst doesn't deserve your land, Charlie.
我也不应该忘记
Nor ought I either fail to bring to mind
那个混蛋有前科
the bastard's disposition to foul play.
谈判开始前
Before negotiations commence,
我想我亲自去拜访赫斯特会不会不合适?
would I be out of place calling on Hearst myself?
我也在想 你能给我弄一件尿不湿吗
I wonder, too, might you procure me an infant's linen?
你这样说话朋友都没得做了 查理
And you don't make a friend a stranger, Charlie.
把别人拒之门外
Decline him walking beside you.
先说 我很感激
Saying first, my being grateful
衷心感谢
and heartily appreciative,
我会帮你的朋友最好地
I'd hold with your friend best achieving
实现他自己的目的
his purposes toting his water himself.
今晚一起吃晚饭
Join us for dinner tonight.
你对我儿子从你耳朵里变硬币感到惊奇
You amaze my boy pulling coins from your ears.
要是赫斯特能从我的屁股上
Better trick would be me pulling
变出好几百个就好了
Hearst's hundreds out my ass.
7点等你 查理舅舅
Expect you 7:00, Uncle Charlie.
谢谢 布洛克
Thanks, Bullock,
走好
for the lookout.
早上好 新来的小姐
Good morning, Miss Newly-Arrived!
我猜你是这儿的老板吧
Might you be the establishment's operator?
请叫我艾尔
Named Al.
斯威伦根家最后一人
Swearengen's the remainder,
如果你不觉得这名字
if you ain't overmuch gave pause
太拗口的话
to the various ins and outs.
可以叫我卡罗琳 斯威伦根先生
My name's Caroline Woolgarden, Mr. Swearengen,
我想这不会比你的名字
which I imagine don't slide easy off the tongue
更易脱口而出
any more than yours does.
卡罗琳·乌尔哥登 溜得像黄油
Caroline Woolgarden, like butter.
初来乍到 希望能租到一间舒适的房间
Come new to town in hope of renting one of your fine rooms.
有白痴来了
Shitbird in prospect.
失陪了 乌尔哥登小姐
Would you excuse me, Miss Woolgarden?
真是稀客啊
Ah, produce
乔治·赫斯特先生
George Hearst Esquire,
来自加州的商业巨子 初级参议员
colossus of commerce, junior senator from California,
看来自我们上次邂逅以来
who since our paths last crossed
你变得越来越有权势了
has went from strength to stronger strength still.
就像你说的那样
Even as you name me,
我在这里也算是一个人物 斯威伦根先生
a figure to be reckoned with in this camp, Mr. Swearengen,
今天早晨
I have been made this morning,
我在某种程度上
more than somewhat,
有点不太舒服
to look an incompetent.
你吗 先生
You, sir?
不舒服吗 怎么会这样
An incompetent? Now, how would that ever be?
许多年过去了 我想让你再重温一下
These years now past, I'd have you recall
当年我被袭击的那件事
my having been attacked.
枪袭
Shot,
似乎是一个妓女干的
and near as not, done in by a whore,
之前我知道她的名字
whose name, if I ever knew it,
但现在却已经不记清了
has now been lost to me.
我隐约记得那件事
I dimly recall the matter.
不知民的妓女开始了复仇计划
The nameless whore embarked on a program of vengeance,
而且 天哪 她差点就成功了
and, by God, she nearly brought off.
重点是她企图谋杀我
Referring to her attempt to murder me.
画面不难想象
Not to pretty the picture.
我一直相信
I have lived
这件事已经解决了
believing the matter had been settled.
而且对此我深信不疑
And I was satisfied in that belief.
但现在 我意识到我被耍了
But now, I realize I was tricked.
躺在棺材里的那个妓女根本不是那位枪手
The whore you presented in the box was not the shooter at all.
参议员 您可真是异想天开啊
Ah, you're going for the long, larger-minded view, Senator.
这基于线人给我的信息
Which depends on running telephone lines across the claims.
若能认识到共进之处
On recognizing common ground,
才能一起面向未来
bringing the future to it.
简要来说
A brief illustration of my point--
先生 你说话有简短吗
Does brevity exist in your repertoire, sir?
我正在向查理·乌特的土地出价
I am making an offer on Charlie Utter's land.
木材今天早上就已经到了
Lumber for construction arrived this morning.
很自信嘛
Confident, are we?
支持我收购乌特的不动产
Back my bid for buying up Utter's property.
利用你在镇上的地位来影响其他人
Use your position in the town to sway others,
我就不再追究妓女的事儿
and I will drop any counteraction against the whore.
那个袭击我的怀孕妓女
The pregnant whore who attacked me.
够直截了当的 先生
Uncharacteristically straightforward, sir.
发掘你内心深处的本性
Discover your deepest nature,
斯威伦根先生
Mr. Swearengen.
与未来同行
Walk with the future.
你还好吧 艾尔
How'd that do you, Al?
看起来不错吧
Good like it seemed?
现在是管管崔西的好机会
Best time to produce Trixie
让她闭上嘴 好给我脸上贴点金
so I can sell her on silence as virtue.
明白 老板
On it, Boss.
就是这样 用力呼气 呼出来
That's it. Blow it out, just blow it out.
基督 耶稣 圣母玛利亚 约瑟夫
Christ, Jesus, Mary, and Joseph!
约瑟夫 《圣经》中希伯来人部落的祖先
他们已经排着队在支持你了 崔西女士
They're arrayed to support you, Ms. Trixie,
但你才是应该使劲的人
but you're the one who's got to be pushing!
苍天啊 我看上去没在使劲吗 卢阿姨
Which don't I, in Christ, look to be doing, Aunt Lou?
我是丹·多里特
Dan Dority!
艾尔想和崔西谈话
Speaking for Al that needs words with Trixie!
崔西现在没空
Trixie ain't receiving,
回家都很难 请你
hard as she's coming for home. If you'd just
告诉艾尔 我们会找他谈
tell Al, we'll issue word...
-加油 使劲 -别在这个节骨眼上
- Come on, come on. - ...from this quarter
等我们有体力有时间了再说
as we are fucking able!
好的 我听清楚了 医生
Okay. I hear you, Doc.
再使劲一下 崔西
One more push, Trixie.
就是这样
This is it.
-现在我们要再做一件事 -然后
- Now, we doing something. - And...
我们在做啦
Now we doing it.
好了
Okay.
看到他下面了吗
See his business?
是个男孩
You got a boy!
是男孩
A boy.
抱着他
Go ahead,
拍一下他的后背
and slap his backside.
好了
There we go.
崔西
Oh, Trixie.
你好啊 约书亚
Hello, Joshua.
上帝会保佑你的
Lord keep you.
灾星简·康娜妮女士
Ms. Calamity Jane Cannary.
是查理·乌特老先生啊
Charlie Utter.
把你塞进箱子再送上火车可难度不小啊
Some putting odds up train bring you home in a box.
我是来接琼妮·斯塔布斯的
I come to collect Joanie Stubbs.
天啊
Oh, God.
你怎么看斯塔布斯女士的情况
How would you, uh, describe the Stubbs woman's state of affairs?
不同于她所坚持的 我
Not seeing her consistent, I...
我认为琼妮·斯塔布斯沮丧忧郁的情绪
I say Joanie Stubbs' collecting her portion of
越来越重 就像这里的每个人一样
gloom and dismay, just like any of us.
那么
Well, suppo--
查理假如
Suppose, Charlie...
在这种情况下某个人有点性志
say a, a person had a interest in that situation,
在你看来 要怎么提这个比较尴尬
what, by your lights, would be a right way
的话题才比较好呢
of broaching the subject?
我可能会说
I'd maybe say...
你在为她考虑
you been thinking of her,
希望
hoping...
若她也为你考虑的话
if ever she thought of you,
也同样会是这样想的
her thinking would be friendly, too.
把你刚刚说的一字不落写下来 老混蛋
Write me that down to repeat it, you cocksucker.
你是懂得该怎么说  简
You know what to say, Jane.
你也知道该怎么做
What to do.
请你喝酒
I will stand you to a drink.
感情深一口闷
Down it along with you, too, far as that goes.
-就一口 -喝个屁的酒
- One drink. -Fuck one drink.
快找你姑娘去
Go find your girl.
快去找她
Go get her.
贝拉工会
乔安妮·
斯塔布斯
我得找人谈谈
I'd have a word,
和你们管事的也好
either with management,
或者哪个愿意面朝我的姑娘也好
or just some girl ain't on her back just now,
翘着脚的也行
legs straight up in the air!
如果你要找老板
If you want the boss,
乔安妮在楼上
Joanie's upstairs.
她忙吗
Busy?
-我不知道 -不 我们不知道
- I didn't see. - No, we didn't see.
斯塔布斯小姐 我是简·康娜妮
Jane Cannary come a-calling, Miss Stubbs.
您不赶我走的话我会十分感激
I'd be grateful if you'd hold your fire.
每个人都有挺大的空间嘛
Everyone got plenty of room?
好像也还凑合
Seem to be making due.
我和狄妮先出去了 乔安妮
Why don't me and Deenie just get outta here, Joanie?
我们可不想惹麻烦
We don't want no trouble.
来得好啊 简
Well arrived, Jane.
-欢迎回家 - 去你妈的
- Welcome home. - Go fuck yourself.
拿好她的香皂
Hold her soap!
好久不见
Considerable time since seeing you.
我这不是去周游国家 环游世界了嘛
Wasn't me setting off see the country, see the world.
我们确实回不到过去了吗
Weren't we sure as fuck done with each other back then?
我可没这么说过
Not on none of my say-so.
说吧 你想说什么
Well, go on. Say what you wanna say.
就是
Uh, just...
看到你回来了非常高兴
surprised to find you back here is all.
我非常感谢
I'd be grateful
你一直关注着
keeping opinions to yourself concerning
我的行踪和所在地
my whereabouts and purposes.
你想吵架的话就吵吧
You wanna brawl, we can do it.
像我这么大的人了 吵架不太合适
Brawling's unseemly, girl my age.
查理·乌特说你变得越来越好了
Charlie Utter said you been better.
是吗 查理真的这么说吗
Is that right? Charlie did?
我猜你不得不在吸嗨了后
High on dope, as I suppose you'd have to be,
来陪那些可怜虫
consorting with them miserable cunts.
新旧讨厌鬼都有
New old damn shooter coming out.
她深信当她离开了桌子 游戏就结束了
Believed the game shut down when she left the table.
乌特先生 你的这些砂矿地
These placer acres that you own, Mr. Utter,
深深吸引着我
captured my attention.
你是在找你之前派出的侦察兵吧
Scouts you sent previous made that clear.
一个我所尊敬其判断能力的人
People whose judgment I respect
分析这片财产的市场价
assay this property's market value
为3500美金
at $3,500.
似乎就我在前进道路上孤独地坚持着
Seems I'm the lone holdout on the path of progress.
为了些好报
By way of abbreviating our back and forth and...
我们就不一来一回地讨价还价吧
maybe generating some good will,
我再加500美元
I'd go 500 above.
给你
Offer you...
整整4000美元现金
4,000 even, cash money.
我父亲曾经教我
My father taught his boy,
用"猛抓狠打"描述可能会更准确
uh, "beat hell into him" might maybe be more accurate,
如果
how if, uh,
你所投资的土地正在崛起
early enough on,
你又开始得足够早的话
you credited the settlements was coming,
可以先用合理的价格买下它
bought acres reasonable,
适当地开发
developed 'em sensible,
牢牢守住 等待时机
hung onto 'em until the market come right,
有一天你会发现
of a day you might could wake up and find
你做了一个非常满意的投资
you made yourself a respectable investment.
你父亲思想很先进啊
Forward thinking was your father then.
而现在 他的儿子在证实他的预言
And now, here's his boy to confirm his papa's prediction.
恰恰相反
Contrary-wise,
人可能会
man might could...
有一些特殊的情感
come to certain special feelings.
像是一部分
Partial, say,
对一片土地的情感
to a piece of ground.
看着一条河
A river...
就这样从森林中蜿蜒流过
bending through the forest like so.
我拒绝你的买卖 赫斯特先生
I decline your offer, Mr. Hearst,
谢谢你花时间和精力
thanking you for your time
来听我讲故事
and attention.
我多年的经验告诉我
My experience over time has come to be...
该开始谈判了
customarily, I am he who starts a negotiation.
你那些故事和名字也可以结束了
Names its finish, too.
也许今天早上
Maybe getting mother-fucked this morning
一个女人在大道上卖东西
in the thoroughfare, by a woman in the bargain,
而其中有样东西吸引了你回头去看
has somewhat got your back up.
而你就做作地在回头路上
Not the accolade you'd looked for
寻求你那该死的赞美
out your return to fuckin' camp.
先生 评价别人
Proffering that assessment, sir,
不是你职责所在
is hardly your proper bailiwick.
目前来说 我他妈就这么做了
Far as that, I went and proffered it any-fuckin'-way.
在场有没有人
Any soul on the grounds
和海象极其相似
bearing mortal likeness to a walrus,
举起你的右手或吹个口哨
raise up your right hand or whistle.
你 汤姆·纳托尔
You, Tom Nuttall!
把你的右手举起来
Up with your right,
或撅起你的嘴吹口哨
or purse your damn lips and blow!
别白费力气了
Pitiful effort.
欢迎回家 简
Welcome home, Jane.
只是因为某件事
'Scription to propose.
墓碑直立在棺材上
Tombstone above a casket.
就在这个点
"On this spot...
这里坐着比尔·希科克
"Was Bill Hickok
他被粗暴地毙命
"foully slayed,
就一个小子弹就打爆了他的头
"brains blown to bits...
是懦夫杰克·麦考尔动的手
"by the coward Jack McCall!
都沉睡在这底下
"'Neath this building, too,
往后
"days to come,
这重任就要寄托在
"will rest the remains of
简·阿迪斯·康娜妮的身上了
"Jane Ardis Cannary,
不认识我的人只知道我乃灾星
"known as Calamity to strangers,
但对比尔·希科克来说
"and to Bill Hickok
我却是他的知心朋友
"as a very good friend.
在这个
"At the place
他痛苦逝去的地方
"of his sorrowful demise,
愿我的灵魂能在这小心守望
"may Jane's spirit stand vigilante watch
好像在人生中看到了自己的无能
as in life she found herself unable."
说直白点 简
And to speak straightforward, Jane,
你就打算在这定居了
you mortally installed
还要烂在这里
and decaying 'neath this building
而不是给我留下贸易大亨的印象
don't strike me as a magnet for commerce.
因为你不会做生意啊 汤姆
Because you're headless for business, Tom,
然后一不小心 脸都耷拉到靴子上了
and heedless and horse-faced to boot!
为什么不把墓地清一清
Well, why not empty the graveyards?
我们可以把尸体摆在桌子上
We'll spot corpses at the tables,
营造一种阴郁的氛围
needling the gloom overall.
想想都是一股腐臭的味道
That's a rotten idea.
神经病 阿迪
Fuck yourself, Arty.
你在卖什么 吴
What are you selling, Wu?
斯韦德
Swedgin.
给你的
You.
他有药要给你
He has medicine for you.
你脸色不太好
Your color looks wrong.
孟尧 可以雇你跑一趟吗
Mengyao, you for hire?
是的 斯韦德先生
Yes, Mr. Swedgin.
那好
Good.
我要你
I want you to
把这个纸条
take this note
拿给索尔·史达 让他转交给崔西女士
to Sol Star to give to his lady, Trixie,
就在那边的路上的
over at the Bullock Star Hotel
布洛克 史达旅馆里
over the road there.
-懂了吗 -我的酬劳是多少
- You got that? - How much will you pay me?
酬劳等你回来
Payment upon return,
确认完成工作后再给
and job verified complete.
你先到门外等你爷爷
Now go wait outside the door for your granddad.
去等着
wait.
斯韦德 喝 茶
Swedgin. Drink. Tea.
你 喝 茶
You drink tea.
不 不
No! No!
这个不 让我想割掉你的喉咙
I'll cut your chink throat for a "no,"
再把你和门外那个一起扔下阳台
and pitch you off the balcony with the other one,
掉下去的时候记得把舌头捋直
seek health advice on the way down.
去你妈的姓吴的
Fuckin' Wu.
出去 回该死的小地方去
Go on, get back to your fuckin' alley!
去你妈的茶
Fuckin' tea, huh?
我做错什么了吗
Am I doing somethin' wrong?
你让我很为难 你
You gimme the fantods, you're so...
之前在这工作的时候多么讨人喜欢
favoring a girl who once worked here.
她也像我这样穿长袜吗
Is she thick through the calf like me?
她很漂亮
She's pretty.
她有最亮的秀发 最甜的笑容
She had the yellowest hair. Just the sweetest damn smile.
还掉了一颗牙 就在
She had a chip, she had...
那儿 对在那儿 简直让人神魂颠倒
there, right there, like to drive a fella crazy.
至少让我是这样
Me at least, anyway.
珍
Jen...
是她的名字
her name was.
珍走了吗
And Jen move along?
是 她走了
She, she did. Uh-huh.
她走了
Moved on.
告诉你去哪了吗
Give you word where?
我之前没说实话 卡罗琳
I weren't telling you true, Caroline.
她去世了
She died.
珍死了
Jen did.
这很不幸
Just poor luck...
她明明什么都没做
Caught in the middle of situation none of her
却被迫拉入困境
fuckin' doing.
如此甜美的灵魂
"Exceptional sweet soul,"
牧师这样评价她
Minister said.
但他没有错
And he weren't wrong.
直到你放下她之前
Appears my job's in progress
似乎我都有工作可做了
before we might even get to set down.
过早的勃起…
Early uprising...
对我来说是漫长的考验
longtime trial to me.
查理迟到了一个多小时
More than an hour late is Charlie.
也许我因赫斯特对他太苛刻了
Maybe I pressed too hard about Hearst.
也许他还在和其他人聊天
Perhaps he got involved catching' up with folks.
我要给孩子们弄吃的了
I should feed the children.
我出去找一下查理
I'm gonna look out for Charlie.
晚上好 警长
Evening, Marshal!
简 看到查理·乌特了吗
Looking for Charlie Utter, Jane.
今晚我没有见到他
I ain't seen him tonight.
帮我个忙
Do something for me?
麻烦在镇上看看 如果找到查理
Check around town. If you find Charlie,
转告他 我妻子对他的行为很生气
tell him my wife's angry at his bad behavior.
- 没问题 - 哈利 和我一起
- Count on it! - Harry, with me.
我痛风得厉害
My gout's agitating.
-我可以带一个年轻人去吗 -可以
- Should I take one of the young ones? - Yes, sir.
我他妈会跟你去 布洛克
I'll fucking go with you, Bullock.
不 不
No! No!
我起来了 我起来了
I'm up! I'm up.
那是查理的马
That's Charlie's horse.
从那里开始找吧
Start over there.
保持警惕
Careful now!
你站这多久了
How long you standing out here?
感觉像是我操蛋的生活中美好的一部分
Better part of my fuckin' life, feels like.
你要和我一起找查理·乌特
You looking for Charlie Utter with me or not?
他有时候会到新的地方玩牌
He sometimes plays cards at this new place.
就因为我曾嘲笑过他
Only knowed that 'cause I teased him
他就不常在这出现了
never frequentin' this joint.
带路吧
Lead the way then.
查理
Charlie?
查理·乌特
Charlie Utter!
查理
Charlie!
出来 把手举到我能看到的地方
Come out, hands where I can see 'em.
别开枪
Don't you shoot.
你在这做什么 萨缪尔
What are you doing out here, Samuel?
我只是在拿我的鱼竿
I'm just reaching for my fishing pole,
请你们不要杀了我
and I'm askin' you not to kill me.
上帝啊 查理
Christ. Charlie!
不是我 先生
It weren't me, no sir!
你他妈在说什么
What the fuck you talkin' about?
布洛克呀
Bullock!
全能的耶稣啊
Jesus God in Heaven.
哈利 给他盖上毯子
Get him a blanket, Harry.
-不是我做的 警长 -别动
- I didn't do it, Marshal - Be still.
希望赫斯特先生会知道
I'd appreciate Mr. Hearst knowing
我在这等着和他谈谈
I'm waitin' to talk to him.
-那是乌特先生 -这不可能
- Mr. Utter! - That can't be!
你们看到了吗 浑身是血
You see? Covered in blood!
赫斯特先生 查理·乌特死了
Charlie Utter's dead, Mr. Hearst.
被人谋杀
Murdered.
警长 你知道 乌特先生死于谁手吗
Do we know by whose hand, Marshal, Mr. Utter has been taken?
谁开的枪
Who pulled the trigger,
把肮脏的钱拿出来就完事了
put the fucking money up to get it done.
先生 你这是诽谤
I take that, sir, as a slur
就为了激怒我
meant to incite me.
我不会让你得逞的
And I do not choose to be provoked.
先生 你预判乌特先生的死与我有关
Your imputing foreknowledge, sir, to me of Mr. Utter's murder
我不想接受这可耻的诋毁
exposes me to shameful slander and disesteem.
我请你收回你的观点
I will have you recant.
不然就准备好
Or either ready to receive
接受我的指责
behavior from me in rebuke.
你会如何指责我呢
What form then do you figure your rebuke will take,
难道也是像你之前杀妓女一样
murdering cunt that you are?
-布洛克 -我一会再去找你
- Bullock. - I'll get to you in a fuckin' minute.
查理·乌特呀
Charlie Utter.
请为这个好人的死而哀悼
Have a thought for a good man dead.
关门了 酒馆要关门了
Shut the place down. Bar's closed!
都他妈的从这滚出去
Go on, get the fuck outta here!
我要学着在你和该死的赫斯特
I'd learn the import of that look
之间做做样子
passed twixt you and fuckin' Hearst.
给警长拿杯威士忌
Get the marshal a whiskey.
我他妈什么都不想喝
I don't want a fuckin' drink.
所以 布洛克
Say, Bullock,
这家伙没用多少时间处理他的应尽事务
a fella, not many hours left to order his affairs,
而是花在了其他事情上
applied them that remained, naming such
还美其名曰需要优先处理
purposes that he'd give primacy.
不管你答不答应 艾尔
Deal me in or don't, Al.
我他妈才不会半途而废
I'd not be fucked halfway up.
赫斯特来过 假装大发慈悲
Hearst stopped by, wanted to bury the hatchet.
想用用少得可怜的钱和影响力
Pool revenue and influence
来换崔西的命
in exchange for Trixie's life.
他计划在乌特的地产上铺电话线
Planning to run telephone wires across Utter's property.
木材都要按他的要求摆
Lumber lies at his claim.
他把这些告诉你时 你他妈的怎么说
Him conveying that to you, you said fuckin' what?
-我同意了 -结果呢
- I let the offer sit. - To what fucking end?
布洛克 你说话可以委婉一点吗
You ever think, Bullock, of not going straight at a thing?
不能
No.
接下来呢 艾尔
What's the move, Al?
我真希望我他妈的知道
Wish the fuck I knew.
杀了查理·乌特就改变了游戏规则
Killing Charlie Utter changes the game.
有个目击证人可以作证
Say the man has an eyewitness to bring to bear.
他叫什么名字
Name him.
萨缪尔·费尔德
Samuel Fields.
这位黑鬼将军能作什么证
The Nigger General was an eyewitness to what?
为查理·乌特作证
Eyewitness to them as did for Charlie Utter.
因此我们需要一场他妈的完美的谋杀
And thereby need a good fuckin' murdering.
我们必须守法
Sidestepping legal administration.
如果连赫斯特都不遵守法律
Well, if it ain't for Hearst to follow the law,
你他妈还遵守个鬼
why the fuck should it be for you?
布洛克 你脸上这幅鬼表情是什么意思
Now, how should I construe that look on your mug, Bullock?
艾尔 我的职责不是遵守法律
My job ain't to follow the law, Al.
而是先理解法律
My job is to interpret it,
再依法行事
then enforce it... accordingly.
你最好规劝一下你的伙伴
You best counsel your partner proper,
确保其母亲和孩子的安全
the safety of mother and child.
索尔和我会负责的
Sol and me'll see to it.
赫斯特很快就会
Hearst won't take long
暴露他那恶心腐败的本性
before he honors the rigors of his putrid fuckin' nature.
他会遭报应的
He'll want an answer.
我帮你会转告的
I'll deliver your fuckin' answer.
电话在我的房间里
Fuckin' telephone in my joint.
酒馆是一个避难所
Saloon is a sanctuary.
每个人都配拥有
Every man worth the name
识而不得的价值
knows the value of being unreachable.
斯威伦根先生 请允许我现在服侍你
Will you have me suck your prick now, Mr. Swearengen?
我拒绝你之后你会改变心意吗
What has changed since early when I declined the offer?
我看起来像是会马上变得金枪不倒吗
Do I look suddenly robust, unimpededly erect?
我告诉过你 我不行了
I am out, as I told you,
应酬 活动 啥都不行了
of sorts, commission, activity.
甚至越来越记不住所有
And more and more forgetful what the whole
明示了的下流污秽的事
sordid fuckin' business is to signify.
我不介意被忘记
Plenty I wouldn't mind forgetting.
过来这里 过来
Hey, come over here. Come on.
之前你弄掉了这个
You dropped this earlier.
不管你信不信 我很看重它
Real or not, I value it high.
这可是个珍贵的纪念金币
That is a goddamn gold commemorative
值12到14美元
worth 12 to $14.
你能告诉我今天早上
Can I ask who the woman was earlier today,
在酒店阳台上大叫的女人是谁吗
yelling from the hotel balcony?
一个不怕死的人
One who ain't afraid to die.
你还看到谁了
And who you'd see live?
这就是问题所在
Well, that's the question.
我走了之后 谁来保护她
When I'm gone, who'll protect her?
上帝能有求必应吗 布洛克能吗
Can the Jew do what needs to be done? Can Bullock?
上帝 救救我
Oh Christ, save me.
我对她有感觉吗
Have I feelings for her?
难道我在这年纪失去了一个心爱的女人吗
Am I that fuckin' lost a cunt, a man my age?
令我伤感的是
Makes me wanna weep,
你让我想起了我父亲
how you remind me of my dad.
不要把你莫名的关系缠在我脖子上
Don't you hang your relations around my neck.
这是一个悲伤的夜晚
It's a sad night.
有什么烧着 了
Something's afire.
上帝
Christ.
我确实有感觉
I do have feelings.
敬查理·乌特
Charlie Utter.
把崔西捉拿归案可费了不少劲儿啊
So much to rounding up Trixie for me.
昨晚不是你让小吴回避一下嘛
Well last night, you sent little Wu with a notion to abstain!
是吗
Did I now?
医生并不是百分百赞成
Doc is not 100% all the way to the top persuaded
你现在就起床
that you oughta be up and about just yet.
医生有啥建议他爱咋咋地
Doc's got a call to his own fuckin' opinion,
但不要他妈的
but not to be blabbin'
对我的计划
about what pertains or ain't
指手画脚
to my fuckin' plans, huh?!
真他妈的操透了心
Fucking drenched.
艾尔 你起来干什么
What are you doing up, Al?!
这医生真他妈闲得蛋疼
Well, this is fucking pain in the balls.
老天
Jesus Christ!
我欠查理一次送行 医生
I owe Charlie Utter a sending off, Doc.
该死 艾尔
Oh, goddamn it, Al.
丹
Hey, Dan!
你做到了 不是吗
You do it, huh?
我们每人掬一把泥土给他吧
Handful of dirt from each of us?
敬查理·乌特
Charlie Utter.
♪ 你该独自 ♪
♪ You gotta walk it ♪
♪ 离去了 ♪
♪ by yourself ♪
♪ 旁无一人相伴 ♪
♪ There's nobody else... ♪
乌特先生习惯性地让我穿过他的地盘
Mr. Utter's accustomed to letting me cross
并在分隔他的和赫斯特先生
his land and fish the stream
的土地的小溪里钓鱼
that separates his acres from Mr. Hearst.
我到那里后大概过了15分钟
He come 'round about a quarter
他正好路过
past the second I caught,
我还想着他可能会
me expecting his purpose to
问候我最近怎么样
ask how I was faring.
我听到一声枪响 然后立马就跑了
I heard a rifle shot, and took the fuck off.
你能认出是谁开的枪吗
Could you identify the man who did it?
不 先生 我不能
No, sir, I cannot.
因为我根本没看见他
Because I didn't see him.
你说的是实话吗
You being you?
是的 我的肤色不会改变事实
Me being the color I am, yes, sir.
不过我希望我能
I wish I could.
我再和你说一次 警长
I'ma say this once to you, Marshal.
我会让自己仍抱有希望
I'm gonna let myself hope
关于你不会允许他们因为一些
that you don't permit 'em stringing me up
我他妈完全没做的事情而把我吊死
over something I had nothing to do with, not fuck all.
萨缪尔 现在还没人想用私刑来惩罚你
Nobody's trying to lynch you at this moment here, Samuel.
如果你认真地看着我
And if you look at me hard,
你就会知道
you'll know
他们在绞死你之前
they'll have to kill me down the road
得先从我的尸体上踏过去
before they get to do it then.
希望你在出言不逊之前想清楚了 警长
Bless you seeing clear to say so, Marshal,
并且给我找个好律师
and get me a good goddamn lawyer.
抱歉迟到了 痛风作怪了
Sorry for the lateness. Gout's flaring.
我刚在医生那里
Was at the Doc's.
最近经常听到你痛风的事啊 哈利
Been hearing about your gout a lot lately, Harry.
就像魔鬼拿着小叉在戳我一样
Pokes me like devil's in there working with a tiny pitchfork.
这里什么情况
How's this going?
给我找个好律师 警长
Get me a good goddamn lawyer, Marshal!
♪ 我站立在 ♪
♪ I was standing on the banks ♪
♪ 河流的岸边上 ♪
♪ Of the river ♪
♪ 眺望着 ♪
♪ Looking out ♪
♪ 生命的 ♪
♪ Over life's ♪
♪ 波涛汹涌 ♪
♪ Troubled seas ♪
♪ 当我看到 ♪
♪ When I saw ♪
♪ 水上有一艘 ♪
♪ An old ship ♪
♪ 旧船在航行 ♪
♪ That was sailing ♪
♪ 是那艘 ♪
♪ Is that the old... ♪
来吧 简 查理葬礼时间到了
Come on, Jane. Time for Charlie's burial.
记得比尔去世的时候吗
Remember when Bill passed?
查理过于痛心以至于离开镇上
Charlie so broke up he'd been out the camp,
最后没能赶上葬礼
couldn't attend the goodbye?
我也记得 女孩们几乎都
And I recollect, too, girl barely
比肩接踵地
could put one foot front the other
只为了送比尔·希科克最后一程
but weren't gonna fail to see Bill Hickok off.
当索尔·史达和我来到这个地方的时候
When Sol Star and I came to this community,
查理·乌特
Charlie Utter...
是第一个上前问候的人
was first man forward offering his hand in greeting.
随着时间的推移 索尔和我
Over time, Sol and I formed a...
与查理结下了深厚的友谊
friendship with Charlie.
这丰富了我们的生活
Enriched our lives.
言归正传 他是个善良正义的人
Come up to proper, he was good-natured and just.
无论何时何地
Come to any way at all,
我从未见过有人让他退缩
I never saw a man stand him down.
只有把他
Only right
埋葬在他为之奋斗的土地上才是正确的
he should be buried on the land he worked his life for.
查理被错误地从我们身边带走了
Charlie was took from us wrongful,
他被
and he was...
他被带走得太早了
He was took too soon.
为了一个好人的灵魂
We ask respite
我们在此恳求
for a good man's soul.
求主把他带回家
Pray the Lord carry him home.
没有人像查理一样支持我
No man never stood up for me how Charlie did,
也不必细说以何种方式
nor with no word 'bout doing it, neither.
阿门
Amen.
Amen to that.
先生们
Gentlemen.
参议员赫斯特在等我们
Senator Hearst expecting us.
九号房间
Room number nine.
加州来的马屁精
Constituents of the cocksucker from California?
连一点日常礼貌都不懂吗
Don't I deserve common courtesy?
我为这个镇的镇长服务
May I mention service as this community's mayor,
尽管得承认我们很大程度上持对立态度
albeit admittedly a largely titular position.
但事实就是事实
But, facts are facts.
先生们 可以的话这是你们应得的认可
Well deserved, if modest, recognitions, gentlemen.
干的不错
Jobs well done.
如果你认为给予这份认可
Well, if you call them recognitions
就可以的话 赫斯特先生
just modest, Mr. Hearst,
我向上帝祈祷 你会在
I pray to Christ we run across you
耀武扬威的那一天遇见我们
the day you're showing off.
确定你们没被看见吧
Certain you were unseen?
几英里内荒无人烟
Not a human eye for miles.
丹尼斯 看来这个人脑浆快流完了啊
Man looks to be losing his mind, Dennis.
-那个方向 -什么鬼
- That direction. - What the fuck?
今天早些时候
I saw a fisherman at the claim
有人声称
earlier in the day.
在小溪边看见了
Dark-complected fellow,
一个黑人渔夫
wading the stream.
你让我严重怀疑我们杀的
You bring me to wonder aloud if that last
是个秃头的冒充者
was a bald-faced fabrication.
我的消息来源说警长
My sources say Marshal's
为了收集证据 找到了一个证人
collected a witness, for a fact.
我付钱希望得到的
I paid for execution
是专业级的刺杀
at a level of professional excellence.
你们被委托
You were commissioned...
完成这一份工作
to undertake of certain effort.
也就无需声明
It went without saying that
你们需要处理一切
you would address any complications
可能接踵而至的情况
that might ensue.
这是合同的一部分 先生 是的
Part of the contract, sir, yes.
他们拘留了一个人
They have someone in custody,
这就意味着你们在满足我的需求上
which fails, by a considerable margin,
大大地失败了
to please me.
我强烈建议你们处理好这件事
I strongly suggest you handle it.
我们他妈的该怎么进警察局
How the fuck are we supposed to get into the marshal's office?
以检查这个这个消息的真实性
Check on the veracity of this claim?
我的消息来源可信且并不简单
My sources are to be trusted, it won't be easy.
但是 这也不是不可能的
But, neither will it be impossible.
我懂了
I see.
这附加服务
This further business,
如果成功完成
if successfully brought to fruition,
我会给你们每个人
will earn each of you...
另外的50美元
$50 additional.
这才像话嘛
Well, now we're talkin'.
-黑人渔夫是吗 -这差事不难吧
- The Negro fisherman? - That'd be a job well done.
老天
Judas Priest!
法纳姆先生 借一步说话
A word with you, Mr. Farnum!
我的财产昨晚被纵火
Property of mine fell victim to arson last night.
参议员 我很理解
So, Senator, I'm gave to understand.
多可怕的消息啊
What dreadful news.
订购木材
Place this lumber order.
主要为供应商优先
The vendor is in Lead.
告诉那个人
Tell the man
每周交货 直到另行通知
weekly deliveries until further notice.
发电报吗 先生
By telegraph, sir?
外面有一部公用电话
There is a public telephone just outside.
进步点吧 法纳姆先生
Take the leap, Mr. Farnum.
未来在前方
The future awaits.
先生 队伍一直排得很长
The queue, sir, stretches.
你看到那流氓了吗
Have you seen the riffraff lined up?
他可能会拖延进度
Stall progress he may.
但他无法阻止
Stop it he cannot.
每件生意 法纳姆先生
Every business, Mr. Farnum,
在这片土地上兴旺发达
in this territory thrives
都是沟通后的直接结果
as a direct result of communication.
现在 我们对现代进步的节奏
Now, we've no say as to the pace
没有发言权
of modernity's advance.
我自己也只是 它的容器之一
I myself am merely... its vessel.
如同卑微的步兵一般
A humble foot soldier.
它的必然性才最深刻的真理 --
Its inevitability is the deepest truth--
你到底怎么了 该死的
What is wrong with you, goddamn it, to be
你的脚不停地在动
shifting your feet so incessantly?
每年的这个时候
Uh, the procession of years,
纵欲过度
wanton leakage.
你真恶心
You are a vile creature.
你也不是第一个这么说的了
Nor are you first to say so.
滚出去打电话
Get the hell out and place the call.
我会在最短的时间内完成
I'll detain you for the briefest moment.
-现在 -是的 先生 现在就去
- Now. - Yes, sir. Going.
朱厄尔 桃子是镇上的元老们聚会用的
Peaches, Jewel, are for meeting of the town elders.
而等会我们就要面对一场拍卖会
This prospect here before us, it's an auction.
这他妈就不是一回事
It's hardly the same fuckin' thing.
老天爷 你就不能找点事干吗 丹
God, you think about ever getting yourself a hobby, Dan?
小嘴再叭叭叭 信不信老子
And that smart-ass mouth of your'n is gonna get you
把你调回厨房打杂去
relegated back to the fucking kitchen.
这对赫斯特无效
Futile to go to Hearst this way.
不管他的后台怎么样 但很遗憾
No matter his resources, but it'd be a pity
他没有意识到危在旦夕的是什么
not to recognize what's at stake.
盲目前行 然后愚蠢地死去
To go ahead and die stupid.
他不想到死都是一个傻子 是吗
Hate to end a fool, right?
查理·乌特肯定不是
Sure as hell Charlie Utter didn't.
你只需要记住一点 做好分内的事
What's essential is you remember, do your part.
还有其他吩咐吗 警长
Oh, naught else, Marshal?
有要洗的衣服吗
Laundry required?
有的话我叫你
I'll let you know.
你去哪了 布洛克
Where you been, Bullock?
去街上转了转 艾尔
Right up the fuckin' road, Al.
妈蛋
God damn it!
破玩意儿
Goddamn it.
我的妈呀 能出个声不
My goodness. A voice?
你好啊 对面的朋友
Hello, in there.
我要找里德镇管事的
I'm calling the town of Lead!
这里是E.B. 法纳姆 朽木镇镇长
It's Deadwood's mayor, E.B. Farnum,
现在屈就富商乔治·赫斯特议员的仆人
relegated to magnate-Senator George Hearst's errand boy,
议员先生命我告知伐木供应商
calling Lead Lumber at the senator's behest.
这件事结束之前 那个黑人必须得死
The Negro will lay slain before this concludes.
天呐 我得去找布洛克
Christ. I must get to Bullock.
下午好 欢迎来到
Good afternoon and welcome to
乌特的财产拍卖大会
the Utter estates dispersal,
此次拍卖会将在
as will proceed
朽木银行的监管下进行
under the supervision of the Deadwood Bank.
拍品的尺寸和细节
A description of the parcel and its dimensions
都已经尽可能详细的为各位罗列
are detailed in the available literature.
第一项拍品 查理·乌特名下的土地
First bids on landholdings of Charlie Utter,
受托人 朽木银行
Deadwood Bank the fiduciary,
起拍价 两千五美金
to commence at $2,500,
每次竞价将以一百美金为单位递增
increments thereafter of $100 above the previous bid.
我可干不了这么复杂的事
I'm not made for such complexity.
谁将为今天的第一件拍品
Who will open now on parcel one
出价两千五美金呢
at $2,500?
我出价2500美金
I've a bid for $2,500
竞拍饮恨离世的乌特先生
on the regrettably deceased Mr. Utter's
这块令人垂涎的土地
very desirable property.
有人出价两千六吗
Who will go with me now to 26?
-我出两千六 -支持你 搭档
- $2,600. - Backing your play, partner.
保守谨慎
Conservative proffer.
我出两千七
Uh, $2,700.
赫斯特一口咬住对手的要害
Upon which Hearst takes matters by the neck.
三千
3,000.
我也是下得了狠心的
Nor do I lack for stronger opinions.
-三千一 -三千二
- 3,100. - 32.
警长 你是骑着特洛伊的木马进来的吗
Rode in, did you, Marshal, on a Trojan horse?
意为来者不善
有人出价三千二
Floor's heard $3,200.
三千三
3,300, please.
三千四 警长 跟不上不要勉强
34. And if you know your limit, Marshal,
咱们快点结束
let's hurry and get to it so that I may get us past,
还能正好赶上晚饭时间
and that we all of us can sup at a decent hour.
三千四百美金 一次
3,400's heard once.
三千五
3,500.
昨晚的火烧得真是旺啊
Terrible fire at your claim last night.
各位
Everybody whole,
-议员 -三千六
- Senator? - 36.
三千七百美金
3,700.
三千八
38.
三千九
3,900.
三千九百美金 一次
I've 3,900 once.
赫斯特先生派我们来的
Mr. Hearst sent us.
还他妈是白天呢
It's fuckin' daytime.
有什么鸟关系
Not our fuckin' problem.
说吧 你想怎么来
Say how you want it played.
钥匙在桌上 打这边
Key's on the desk, this side of my head.
-四千三 -四千四
- 4,300. - 44.
-赛斯 -有人出四千五吗
- Seth... - Do I hear 4,500?
五千 妈的
5,000, goddamn it.
这个数应该能把观光的吓走了吧
As ought shoo the sightseers off.
-五千五 -五千六
- 5,500. - 56.
六千
6,000.
六千五
6,500.
七千美金
$7,000.
七千二
7,200.
七千三百美金
$7,300.
二位先生 你们如果继续出价
And neither, if you continue, sir,
可不会再有人跟了
will you find yourself unaccompanied.
七千三百美金
I've $7,300
竞拍乌特的地产 一次
for the Utter property heard once.
七千三百美金 两次
7,300 twice.
三次
Third time.
高贵又足智多谋的埃尔斯沃斯夫人
Sold to the distinguished and resourceful
以7300美金的价格 成交
Mrs. Ellsworth, for $7,300!
埃尔斯沃斯夫人
Mrs. Ellsworth.
查理以你为荣
You honored Charlie today.
布洛克
Bullock!
失陪一下
Excuse me.
怎么了 E.B.
What is it, E.B.?
-你确定吗 -确定
- You're certain? - Yes.
丹啊
Dan.
-叫上 艾尔 -待着别动
- With Al. - Staying.
不要
No!
对不起
Sorry.
过去多久了
How long ago?
我也说不准
I couldn't tell you for a mortal truth.
-他们把萨缪尔带走了 -警长
- They got Samuel. - Marshal!
快来 不好了 快来
Come! Something bad is happening! Come!
快点 来这边
Come! Come here!
放我走 我就放了这个兔崽子
Lemme go, the chink lives.
孟尧 孟尧
Mengyao! Mengyao!
敢动手你就死定了
You're gonna die you do that.
你要逮捕我吗 因为我打了这个
You arresting me for beating a coon
谋杀白人的黑鬼几下
murdered a decent white man?
查理·乌特是你杀的
You murdered Charlie Utter.
是吗 谁说的
Aye? And who says so?
我
I...
是我说的
I say so.
布洛克 就是他
That's him, Bullock.
杀了你的朋友
Killed your friend.
赛斯
Seth.
赛斯 赛斯
Seth! Seth!
别打死了
Don't kill him!
照顾好萨缪尔
Take care of Samuel.
吴 把那个东西拿去喂猪
Wu, feed that fuck to the pigs.
乔治·赫斯特 出来
George Hearst! Come out!
乔治·赫斯特啊
George Hearst!
滚出来
Come out now!
是谁指使你杀害查理·乌特的
Identify the man hired you to do Charlie Utter's murder.
终于失控了吗 警长
Finally lost your grip, Marshal.
是谁 说
Name the man! Go on!
把他指出来
Point him out.
是他雇的我们
He hired us.
谁
Who did?
想陷害我是吗 警长
Set up, Marshal, are we?
正义与仁慈相得益彰
Justice and mercy in proper relation.
觉得自己更爷们了吗
Feelin' more a man?
最好把下一批木材控制起来
Better lock the next shipment of lumber up.
你的勋章最好能保你
I expect you believe a badge
免受某些不良后果的影响
insulates you from certain untoward consequences.
就像你的议员身份
Much as your being a US senator
最好可以护你免遭牢狱之灾
will insulate you from jail.
让这个狗娘养的放下武器
Tell this cocksucker to lower his weapon!
都进去
Inside, now.
我中弹了
Fuckin' shot, I am!
死不了
You'll fuckin' live.
约翰尼
Johnny...
恭喜你手里又多了几条人命
Congratulations on the rising body count.
我不觉得有什么可骄傲的
Ain't proud of it.
我会来找你算账的 警长
I'm coming for you, Marshal.
我等着你 议员先生
Expect you will, Senator.
赫斯特先生
Mr. Hearst?
抱着你儿子
Hold your son.
哄他睡着 给他喂奶
Rock him towards sleep. Feed him his milk
我已经挤到奶瓶里了
I've squoze into his bottles.
要是尿了就给他换洗尿布
Clean and change him when he does his business.
等等 崔西 你要去哪
Wait, Trixie, where are you going?
先是艾尔急匆匆的打电话说要见我
First, Al's urgent call to see me.
然后 他又派人送来另一套说辞
Then, he sends this note sayin' the opposite.
你怎么了 索尔
What the fuck, Sol?
不是我的血
Not mine.
附带的罢了
Collateral damage is all.
那是谁的血啊
Well, whose fucking blood is it?
杀害查理的凶手 已经死了
Men who murdered Charlie, dead now.
先祖显灵了吗
Oh, the Hebrew takes to arms!
崔西 你冷静点
Trixie, please calm down.
那抱着他
Then, take him.
-不要 -看在上帝的份上
- No. - For God's sakes.
我要去见艾尔
I'm getting Al's counsel.
孩子留给了他爹
With our baby stood with his father,
再过他娘的20多分钟
20 possible minutes or a fucking cunt hair more.
我就从旅店的后门出去
I'll exit back of the hotel,
像个贼一样悄咪咪的
sneaky as a mouse,
溜到酒馆前的小路上
and enter the Gem a side way.
又愚蠢又冲动的娘们
Being stupid and fuckin' reckless.
你个犹太混蛋 也许我就是愚蠢又冲动
As I may be both, you Jew bastard,
才选择踏出这道门
to get out the fuckin' door.
打到了你的脑袋和肩膀吗 老头
Beatin' you about head and shoulders, lad?
他们刚刚占了上风
Their's the upper hand just now.
你的某些选择 让你被赫斯特注意到了
Some choice, making your presence known to Hearst.
不管我惹了什么麻烦
Whatever trouble I caused...
都是因为我突然有了孩子
blame the baby's imminent arrival.
我杀了那个小女孩是为了救你
I took that young girl's life to save yours.
艾尔 求你 别再说了
Please, Al, don't say it again.
珍的脸在我脑海挥之不去
Haunts me, Jen's face does.
你又没抹她的脖子
Weren't you cut her throat,
也没有设计一个差点害死所有人的计划
nor devised a fuckin' plan that nearly got us all killed.
上帝怜悯我
God have mercy on me.
我连一分钟的幸福时光都不配拥有
I don't deserve the one fuckin' minute of happiness,
直到我的新生儿降临
my newborn gave me coming into the world.
我们选了救你这疯女人
We chose you, you loopy cunt.
看你把我们搞的
Look at the fuckin' mess you've give us.
我他妈根本不值得你这样啊 艾尔
I'm un-fucking-worthy, Al!
躺棺材里的应该是我 不是她啊
I belonged in that coffin, not her!
行吧 如果你一心求死的话
Well, if your aim was to die, please,
那我愿意送你一程
allow me to do the honors.
我们都被自己乱七八糟的想法所困扰
We're all of us haunted by our own fucking thoughts,
你就赶紧去黄泉跟她做伴吧
so make friends with her ghost!
随便都可以去死
It ain't going fuckin' anywhere!
对不起
I'm sorry...
真的对不起
for everything.
老天爷开眼了啊
Heavens open up.
她居然还会忏悔
She expresses contrition.
也就是说镇里添了个新生儿
New baby in camp?
是个可爱的小男孩
Lovely little boy.
有其母必有其子的
As born of his mother, he would be.
你有阻止过她的离去吗
Did you try and stop her from leaving?
天啊 能做的我都做了
Nothing I could do. Jesus Christ.
萨缪尔被关起来的事我只告诉过斯威伦根
Swearengen's the only one I told Samuel's in the cage.
他虽非好人 但也绝非告密者
Man may be a lot of things, but he's not a snitch.
照目前的的状况
State he's in, more likely fuckin'
他可能早把那段对话忘没了
forgot the conversation entirely.
让你少惹麻烦的这个要求过分么
Too much ask you stay the hell outta trouble?
不过分 布洛克
No, fuckin' Bullock.
并不过分
Not too much.
我不会再惹是生非了
I will.
艾尔的状况很糟
Not himself, Al weren't.
我从来没见他虚弱成那样
Weak like I never seen him.
去收拾行李
Gather some things now.
我们要在布洛克家过夜
We're spending the night at the Bullock house.
咱们得远离镇中心了
Moving us from the center of town.
索尔 我不想离开这儿
Hate runnin' from him, Sol.
为孩子着想吧
For our boy.
他还能活下来么
What are the odds him comin' to?
他被打得伤势过重
He's severely injured from the beating.
脾脏破裂
Spleen's ruptured.
腹腔积血
Blood in his belly.
没可能了么
Odds on it ending?
人终有一死
All bleeding stops eventually.
索尔 我们应该明天就结婚
We ought marry on the morrow, Sol.
艾尔可能快命不久矣了
Al ain't to be relied on to linger.
我们不必遮遮掩掩地成婚
And we ain't exchangin' secret fuckin' vows,
而是光明正大的向彼此许下诺言
tucked away in hiding.
随时恭候
Free all day.
干得好啊
Oh, well done.
干得漂亮啊
Proud performance.
都他妈直接尿自己一身了
Fuckin' pissed myself.
典礼前二十分钟
Twenty minutes going forward to the ceremony,
以及之后的二十分钟内
nor neither the same interval afterwards.
还有在典礼过程中 都不得通奸
No fornication on the premises.
凭什么她就能抱着孩子
Why does she get to hold him?
因为新娘是我
Because I'm the bride,
这个大喜的日子里老娘说了算
and it's my special fuckin' day.
赶紧去帮把手啊 等什么呢
Lend fucking hands, girls!
好好布置这里
Make the place presentable.
真想娶那个女孩啊
May make that girl my wife.
她肯定是个有恋父情节的女人
She ain't gonna marry no man age enough to be her daddy.
十指纤纤轻掠过我的双眸
Soft hands smoothed my brow.
双葱好似有点点茉莉花香
Wrist smelling like jasmine.
一针一线缝满了我的心房
She sewed the hole in my shoulder closed with needle and thread.
然后趁缝的时候把你钱包偷走呗
Lift your wallet while she's doing it?
丹 你也太阴暗了
That's a dark view of the world, Dan.
医生 我请求您指点迷津
I ask to be enlightened as to
我的生命是否行之将末
the passage of spirit in prospect for me, Doc.
我把人体看作为一个细胞的总合
I take us to be collections of cells,
每个细胞又会在其内部聚集成一个更小的
each aggregate a smaller,
更为独立的生命个体
separate life inside us, and...
随着时间慢慢的流逝
and time slows.
这个小生命体也终将走到尽头
And finally stops.
我这个细胞总和最后也会落得这个下场呗
The fate my cell collections live into as we speak.
艾尔 现在还没有个统一的定论
That ain't so to a mortal certainty, Al.
医生 我不想就这么苟延残喘下去
I'd not prolong the chewing up, Doc, nor the being spat out.
也不想这么窝囊的死
Not go out a cunt.
迈向死亡的过程实在是太丢人了
It's the dispatch I find inglorious.
简直是自欺欺人
The whole delusory fucking self-importance.
-那你还参加婚礼么 -非去不可
- Is it your hope to attend the wedding? - It's my resolve.
那好吧
All right then.
张嘴
Pucker up.
给我吧
I'll take him.
为何觉得自己就应该生而为妓呢
Believe you were born to be a whore?
也许这是最适合我的路吧
Probably doing what I'm fit for.
逼你出来卖的那杂种是费了多大功夫
How hard you suppose the bastard turned you out
才让你信了他那一套鬼话的
had to work to make you think that?
崔西
Trixie.
该上楼了
Got an appointment upstairs.
哎呀 就这么往我脸上打喷嚏
Oh, well, I hope you're proud,
看来你挺自豪的吧
expelling your sneeze in my mug.
艾尔 这可是上帝赐福啊
That's the Lord's blessing come upon you, Al.
是主在亲自俯身吻你的脸颊呢
That's him leanin' down to kiss your cheek.
我就跟你开门见山了吧
Well, I ain't got no time left for fancy dancin'.
若我把店交给你 你怎么看
Your thoughts on me leaving you the joint?
不 我的意思不是说
No, not being either to say
让你接着干老鸨的行当
you have to run women.
但我强烈建议
I strongly endorse that.
把这里改成一个舞厅吧
Make it a dance hall for all of me.
艾尔怎么不从马戏团运来点大象助兴呢
What about the circus elephants, Al,
是不是听着就挺好玩的
producing some novel effect?
崔西 改成舞厅不失为一个好主意
Dance hall, Trixie, ain't a bad idea.
你看你找了个多好的男人啊
Good man you got there!
有情有义
Heart, soul,
脑子也够用
and brains enough to know that he struck lucky
明白自己何德何能才遇见了你
in his female companion.
真是孩子的好榜样啊
Good example for the kid to emulate.
我传授人生经验可是分文不取的
And no fee for the sermon.
失陪一会
Excuse me now.
过来
Hey.
你为何不考虑竞选公职呢
Maybe you oughta think about running for office?
如今当权的都是一帮子庸人
Outnumbered, as we are, by shit-birds.
斯威伦根先生 我会慎重考虑的
Food for thought, Mr. Swearengen.
这个主意
That idea
就当作给你们的结婚礼物了
is my wedding gift to you.
多谢你
Thank you.
听说你在这儿
Heard you was down here.
这匹马原来是查理的
This one was Charlie's.
现在是你的了
Yours now.
相信他也希望如此
Sure he'd want that.
发生康娜妮那件事后
Past when I took what Cy gave me,
我曾希望自己不要再醒过来
I'd pray I wouldn't wake up.
没骨气的怂货 不准再这么说了
You gutless cunt. Don't you speak that way to me again.
我的意思是说那都是过眼云烟了
Nor neither am I saying I feel that way now, is my point.
你
You...
我要你狠狠地吻我
gimme a goddamn kiss and say, "I promise
然后起誓无论多么厌世
I won't fold, no matter how sad I get."
都绝不会动轻生的念头
Or just don't say a word at all then.
现在闭嘴快点来吻我
Just go ahead and give me a kiss and don't say a word.
好吧 这可真是
All right. Well...
这一下让我想起了你吻技有多么高超
You bring to recollection you're a hell of a good kisser.
你还在嚼甘草吗
And you're still chewing that licorice?
相比我其它的罪恶 这可太微不足道了
That's my 12th least-worst sin.
床垫里面有一万四千零五十美元
Time comes, I have $14,057 in the mattress,
等我挂了后你们平分了吧
which you will divide equally.
要是你们为此起了争执
You fight amongst yourselves,
那就祈祷这个世上没有地狱吧
you will wish there was no hell
不然老子再还魂来宰了你们几个
because I will surely come back and cut your fuckin' throats.
-我对你的遗产不感兴趣 -哦是么
- Well, I don't want your money. - Yeah...
瞧瞧
There.
先生们
Gentlemen...
咱们像不像四胞胎啊
can we not appear as quadruplets?
感谢主能使你下床
Bless you for being upright,
能让我牵着你的臂弯
for letting me have my hand on your arm,
还使你可以出尽风头
and for being the showing-up sort that you are.
将复何求
What's else is gravy.
安全送达
Safe passage to us all.
你今天真美 亲爱的
Oh, you're a picture, miss.
谢谢你
Means something.
绕郎三圈
Three times I go around?
有枝可依
Always coming back.
永不离弃
I ain't gave to flight.
正直
Righteousness.
慈爱
Loving kindness.
正义
Justice.
我并不是很懂
For all in my ignorance,
也不是一定要求遵循守据
I, uh, do not hew to the letter of,
但我还是希望
uh, its practice, but I'd hope
这个简约的婚礼
the brief ceremony
可以遵守犹太礼仪
will be respectful to... Jewishness!
再好不过了牧师 尽力就好
Level best, Reverend! A for effort.
孩子 祝福你
Eh, bless you, my son,
感谢你如此体谅
and thank you for understanding.
祝词讲完了
Sermon's over.
可以了
That's all!
现在我要请索菲亚小姐
I'll now ask the young Miss Sofia
将婚戒呈送上来
to come forward with the nuptial rings.
以二位所信宗教赋予之权利
By the powers of each of their religions and practices,
我宣布索尔和崔西结为夫妇
I now pronounce Sol and Trixie man and wife.
该不该让新郎吻你
Should your husband kiss you?
他要敢不吻就睡外面吧
Lest he be sleepin' outdoors.
简 我一直想出去见见世面
Been thinking, Jane. Maybe I'd like to see the world.
比如法兰西是什么样的
For instance, what's France like?
不知道呢
Don't know.
你说的倒是让我有兴趣了
Never wanted to see it till this minute.
欢乐时刻啊
Happy occasion.
爸爸
Papa!
你还好吧
Are you all right?
咱们计划一下怎么用那块土地吧
Let's... figure out what to do with that land.
耶稣 圣母玛利亚 圣人们啊
Ah, Jesus, Mary, Joseph, and all risen saints.
求你三思而后行
For once in your life, resist the urge for utterance.
以我的新生儿为见证
As witness before my newborn child
我希望一切能够重新开始
my hope in beginning again,
我希望双方都保持克制
I pray we forbear from
别再互相折磨
fucking up each other's lives further,
而是和平共处
and live in peace and quiet.
史达夫人 我能察觉到
It seems to me, Mrs. Star,
在你努力讨好我的背后
in coming forward to conciliate me,
你的内心痛苦不堪
you consign yourself to a misery
就像在经历着一次
not unlike a sort of...
酷刑
execution.
这两位是来自邻镇的
These two gentlemen are sheriff and deputy
警长和副警长
from a neighboring town,
我找他们代表我的权益
brought in to represent my interests.
这是里德的拉瑞比警长
Sheriff Laraby from Lead.
我们有一份指控崔西·史达
We have a warrant for the arrest of Trixie Star
谋杀乔治·赫斯特先生未遂的逮捕令
for the attempted murder of Mr. George Hearst.
你给我滚出去
You get the hell outta here.
孩子 请克制自己以免失态
Forbear, son, lest you be undone.
我不是你的孩子
I'm not your son,
你也不是他妈的未来的主宰
no more than you're the boss of the fuckin' future.
是吗 我可自认是未来的继承人
Why, I believe I am its whole inheritor.
这些人在这里没有司法管辖权
These men have no jurisdiction here.
想必你带来的这两人
I'm guessing these two you brought
并不知道你的在这里犯下的滔天大罪
don't know the extent of your crimes here.
此乃查理·乌特命案的主要嫌疑犯
Prime suspect in the murder of Charlie Utter.
你又要把我关起来吗
Are you going to incarcerate me again,
布洛克警长
Marshal Bullock?
这次又要关我几分钟
This time, for how many minutes?
到时候就知道了
Let's find out together.
-手铐有点紧了 -闭嘴
- Little tight on my wrist. - Shut up.
到我的地盘上 你要先给警长打招呼
Come through my town, you stop at the marshal's office first.
至少和同行打个招呼 给点他妈的尊重
Way a fellow lawman would do, showing any fuckin' respect.
很抱歉打搅了各位 请继续庆典吧
Sorry for the interruption. Carry on with the celebration.
笑一个 赫斯特议员
Smile, Senator Hearst!
-把他撵走 -总算走了
- Get him outta here. - Good riddance!
在你把他关起来之前
'Fore you lock him up,
不妨让我们跟赫斯特先生说几句话
no harm you letting us have a word with Mr. Hearst.
代逝去的查理·乌特说几句话
Speaking for Charlie Utter, as is gone from amongst us.
这里怎么回事 怎么了
What's going on here? What's in train?
这个美利坚合众国参议员
This United States of American Senator
买凶谋杀了查理·乌特
had Charlie Utter murdered!
-他是个杀人犯 -毫无悔意
- Yeah! He's a murderer! - Without remorse!
-既没有偿命 -看你往哪躲
- Nor recourse! - Can't hide behind that!
也他妈的没有一点悔过之心
Nor fucking recollection!
我要把你的头给拧下来
I'll tear your head clean off, boy,
看你还能不能回忆起来
if that'll help recollection.
谁再扔东西就别怪我不客气了
Who heaves something next gets dealt with.
-你个天杀的狗官僚 -狗杂种
- You entitled motherfucker! - Son of a bitch.
管好你的人 警长
Steer your people, Marshal.
闭上你的嘴
Shut the fuck up!
谁也不用听谁的
Nobody answering no one!
-想干嘛就干嘛 -你说的真对
-Do what-all they want! - You got that right!
快走 走 快走
Go on now! Go! Go.
悠着点儿 什么鬼
Easy! What the hell?
让我们了结了他吧
Come on, let us finish it.
别去打他了
Leave him be.
天哪
My God...
除非你们所有人都想被我抓起来
Lest I arrest every one of you.
我看不下去了
I've seen enough.
去找个医生来
Get the fuckin' Doc.
是啊 帮这个混账东西疗伤止痛
Oh yeah, let's do allay the cocksucker in his misery.
去找医生 简
Now, Jane!
诅咒你横尸街头
Hope you die in the street.
就像我父亲一样
Like my dad did!
都回家去吧
Go on home, now!
你个狗娘养的
You son of a bitch!
你这出游行示众闹够了没
Have you finished your impotent display?
不 我觉得还不够呢
No, I don't believe I have.
你到时要给我作证 参议员
You're my witness, Senator.
我因警长要杀你才开的枪
Marshal's trying to kill you.
这懦夫想从背后阴你 布洛克
Coward was coming behind you, Bullock.
从背后一枪崩了你
'Bout to shoot you back the head.
简
Jane!
你个狗娘养的 哈利
You son of a bitch, Harry.
刚那会儿我被比尔附身了
That was Bill come into me.
他回来保护我们了
Him come to protect us.
不 简 那只是你而已
No, Jane. That was you.
警长啊
The Good Book, Marshal...
《圣经》上说
says...
上帝挑选的见证人
the Lord chooses amongst His witnesses...
会是看起来最不可能的那个
them'd be thought least likely.
是吗
Is that so?
你也许应该知道
You might should oughta know...
在事情发生前
before what happened...
乌特先生
Mr. Utter...
看起来
seemed to me...
像变了一个人
a different man.
像是刚刚如释重负
Like a weight had come off his shoulders.
你知道《圣经》上关于见证人
What else they say
还怎么说吗
about the Lord's witnesses?
怎么说
What else?
他们的缺点
Their defects...
暂时抛开不谈
notwithstanding,
他们见证了
they testify to His
主的神迹
wond'rous glory.
警长 他在弥留之际唱着歌
Singing, he was, at the end, Marshal,
唱着他在山谷徜徉
'bout walking the valley.
听起来愉悦而扣人心弦
Joyful to hear and behold.
就这样唱着
Singing.
如果你肯听我的话
If you have it in you to abide,
我是不会让你离开我的
I'd not have you leave me.
我不会离开的 艾尔
I won't, Al.
时辰到了 我和朱厄尔会陪你到最后
Comes to it, Jewel and me will see to you.
我会让人把孩子抱过来
I'll have the little one brought in.
我前几天听见你在唱歌
I heard you singing the other day.
我还以为是哪只青蛙被你踩到了呢
I thought you'd stepped a frog.
如果你需要的话 艾尔
If you want, Al,
我可以给你按摩脚 手虽有点抖
I can rub your feet, shaky hands,
不过挺好使的
but it works well.
来吧
Go ahead then.
♪ 在丛林里流浪 ♪
♪ Waltzing Matilda ♪
丛林流浪 澳洲代表性民谣 含轻微自杀意味题材
♪ 在丛林里流浪 ♪
♪ Waltzing Matilda ♪
♪ 你随我在丛林流浪 ♪
♪ You'll come a-waltzing Matilda with me ♪
♪ 有一只绵羊 ♪
♪ Down came a jumbuck ♪
♪ 下到水塘喝水 ♪
♪ To drink at the water hole ♪
♪ 流浪汉跳起来 快活地逮住它 ♪
♪ Up jumped the swagman and grabbed him in glee ♪
♪ 他一边唱着一边把羊 ♪
♪ And he said as he put him away ♪
♪ 塞进褶布袋里 ♪
♪ In the tucker bag ♪
♪ 你随我在丛林流浪 ♪
♪ You'll come a-waltzing Matilda with me ♪
♪ 在丛林流浪 在丛林流浪 ♪
♪ Waltzing Matilda, waltzing Matilda ♪
♪ 你随我在丛林流浪 ♪
♪ You'll come a-waltzing Matilda with me ♪
查理·乌特
长眠于此
我回来了
I'm home.
我们
Our Father...
在天上的父
which art in Heaven...
请让他
Let Him
待在天上吧
fucking... stay there.
全片终